A Finding Aid to the Tomás Ybarra-Frausto Research Material on Chicano Art, 1965-2004, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ybartoma
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1965-1997; Series 1
  - Califas: Chicano Art and Culture in California, Conference, Porter College, University of California at Santa Cruz (April 16 - 18, 1982) (Box 4)
    - Seminar, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      (TYF's notes from the planning seminar for CALIFAS)
    - Social Context, circa 1981; (see also: OV 32) (Box 4, Folder 16)
      (working draft of TYF's essay which appeared in the catalog; oversize exhibition poster)
    - Tapes (partial transcript), circa 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Tino Esparza Interview, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      (TYF's notes)
    - TYF Contributions, circa 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      (draft of TYF's CALIFAS California Chicano Art and Its Social Background - Final copy included in CALIFAS publication; letter to TYF from Bob F-[?], 09/21/1981; clippings; TYF's notes on Chicano Art & Culture)
    - Writings, circa 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      (photograph - group photo of participants?, duplicate; poster for exhibition; pages from the catalog; "Califas: 'Chicano Art and Culture in California' 4 Essays [authors: Montoya, Malaquias and Lezlie Salkowitz; Goldman, Shifra M.; Montoya, Jose; Cockcroft, Eva and Centro Cultural de la Raza]; clippings; general correspondence and other documents related to CALIFAS)
    - CALIFAS Seminar, Mary Porter Sesnon Gallery, Porter College, UCSC, 1982; (3 copies of catalog) (Box 4, Folder 21-23)
    - Narrative Report of Accomplishment, University of California, Santa Cruz, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      (final report to the National Endowment for the Humanities)
  - Califas: Chicano Art and Culture in California continued (Box 5)
    - Indexes to the Archive, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Transcripts, Book #1, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Transcripts, Book #2, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Transcripts, Book #3, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Transcripts, Book #4, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Transcripts, Book #5, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Transcripts, Book #6, circa 1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - California (see also Alamaraz, Carlos; Baca, Judy; Benavidez, Max; Botello, David; Dí de los Muertos; Gamboa, Harry Jr.; Gamboa, Manazar; Gronk; Herron, Willie; Hernandez, Judith; Norte, Marisela; Valadez, John), circa 1974-1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    (exhibition announcements; clippings; catalogs; journal, 201: Homenaje a la ciudad de Los Angeles: Latino Experience in Literature and Art, Los Angeles; Latino Writers Workshop, January 1982; photographs of art [not labeled]; unlabeled slides)
  - California Arts Council, 1980; (clipping) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - California Directory of Chicano-Latino Artists (see also: Concilio de Arte Popular), 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    (publication of the Concilio de Arte Popular, Los Angeles, California. Directory, compiled and published by Concilio de Arte Popular: Coalition of California Chicano-Latino Artists, listing contact information as well as specializations, awards, education)
  - California Institute of Arts, Organization, Valencia, California, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    (letters to TYF from Steven D. Levine, 01/26/93; material related to the "Conference on Aesthetics of Community-Based Artmaking" in which TYF participated)
  - California Missions, 1977; (Arte Chicano paintings, clipping) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Campusano, Jesus "Chuy,", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    (exhibition announcement; TYF's notes on a folder)
  - Canadian Club Hispanic Art Tour, Catalog, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Canto al Puerto, Festival, Corpus Christi, Texas, 1978; (ephemera: arm band, bumper stickers; clippings; festival announcement) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Caracol, Newspaper, San Antonio, Texas, February 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Cardenas, Gilberto (see also: Malagamba, Amalia), 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    (typescript, "Las Mujeres de la Raza" by Cardenas and Amalia Malagamba), May 1990; SOC 348K/MAS 374 and SOC 360M course syllabi and related materials, taught by Cardenas)
  - Caricaturista de México, 1983; (clipping) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Carnaval, Rio de Janeiro, 1986; (clipping) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Carrasco, Bárbara (see also: Galería de la Raza/Studio 24), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    (exhibition announcement; monograph, clippings; Artist Monograph Series #3: Barbara Carrasco, Galería de la Raza/Studio 24, San Francisco, 1989)
  - Carrillo, Eduardo L., 1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    (exhibition checklist; catalog; resume; Sueños performance announcement; TYF's notes and interview with Carrillo; clippings)
  - Carrillo, Graciela (see also: Sigüenza, Herbert), 1981; (exhibition announcements) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Casa de la Raza, Organization, Santa Barbara, California, 1978; (clipping) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Casa de Unidad Cultural Arts and Media Center, Organization, Detroit, Michigan, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    (note to TYF re his visit and presentation from Casa de Unidad staff members; El Barrio Magazine Spring/Summer 1991)
  - Casa El Salvador, Convocation Announcement, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Casa Zapata Mural, Stanford University (see also: Burciaga, José), circa 1985-1989 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    (clippings; Lector: The Hispanic Review Journal, vol.5 no.2; Stanford Chicano Murals project, Chicano Research Seminar, material, including statement of background & goals, a working timeline, notes from brainstorming sessions and meetings - product of "Murals as Social Conscience Art"; letter to TYF from José Antonio Burciaga of Casa Zapata, Stanford University, re. the mural that was "conceived and painted" by TYF, 02/18/86; mural survey and responses)
  - Casas, David Zamora, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    (exhibition announcements; clippings; artist biography; photocopy of Pace Roberts Foundation International Artist-in-Residence Program application with artist statement and resume)
  - Casas, Mel, 1965-1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    (catalogs; exhibition announcements; clippings; artist biography; photocopy of "Art of the Southwest...Art on the Border" [booklet?])
  - Casasola, Agustin Victor, Photographer (see also: Photography), undated; (exhibition brochure) (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Castellon, Rolando, 1984, undated; (exhibition announcements) (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Castillo, Ana, 1986, undated; (book publication announcements) (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Celebración Año Nuevo Mexicano, Chispa, Chicago, Illinois, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    (booklet from event has photos from event, as well as a poem and description (copyright 1982, CHISPA)
  - El Centro Chicano, Stanford University (see: Casa Zapata Mural) (Box 5)
  - Centro Cultural Aztlán, Organization, San Antonio, Texas, 1990, undated; (brochures) (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Centro Cultural de la Gente, San Jose, California, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    (exhibition announcement; information brochure on El Centro de la Gente de San José; El Mitote Cultural, newsletter vol.1 no. 2)
  - Centro Cultural de la Mission, Organization, San Francisco, California (see also: Mission District), 1990-1991; (clippings) (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Centro Cultural de la Raza, San Diego, California, 1970-1984; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 36-38)
    (exhibition announcements; clippings; Teatro Mestizo information sheet; TYF's notes on theater; TENAZ Festival Magazine (Chicano Theatre Festival publication, 1977); catalogs; 10th Anniversary Celebration booklet, 1981; Press release; catalogs; clippings; 15th anniversary catalog, Made in Aztlan, Centro Cultural de la Raza, San Diego, 1986; exhibition announcements; letter to TYF from Veronica Enrique, Executive Director, Centro Cultural de la Raza, 04/23/1985; letter to TYF from Philip Brookman, curator, Made in Aztlan, re. the catalog, 02/26/1986; handwritten draft of letter (reply) to Brookman from TYF, undated (on back of Brookman's 2nd letter); TYF's notes and draft of essay for 15th anniversary catalog; TYF's notes on Centro Cultural; Exhibition brochure; organization's brochure; clippings; View (Museum of Contemporary Art San Diego Quarterly Magazine), Jan-March 1993; catalogs; schedule of events)
  - Centro de Artistas Chicanos, Organization, Sacramento, California (see also: Royal Chicano Air Force), 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    (clippings; booklet, "El Espejo del Movimiento" Centro de Artistas Chicanos, RCAF, 1977; TYF's notes on Centro de Artistas Chicanos)
  - El Centro de la Raza, Organization, Seattle, Washington, 1987-1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    (exhibition, performance, and event announcements; handwritten letter to TYF from Robert [?] of El Centro de la Raza, 12/12/1991; invitation; conference brochure - Chicano Mobile Institute, Chicas en el Movimiento)
  - Centro Histórico de la Ciudad de México, Mexico City, Mexico, 1995; (catalog; brochure, Los Nuevos Románticos) (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Centros Culturales, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    (TYF's notes on "Chicano Art: Community and [Communitos?]" and on "Network of Color")
  - Centros de Arte Chicano, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    (TYF's notes on muralists, the history of "El Movimiento"; TYF's outline for "Chicano Art in Social Perspective 1965-1980", etc)
  - Centros de Artistas, undated, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    (TYF's notes on Chicano art and artists)
  - Ceremony of Memory: New Expressions in Spirituality Among Contemporary Hispanic Artists (see also: Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Muñoz, Celia - artist), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    (exhibition, Center for Contemporary Arts of Santa Fe, New Mexico; TYF was a contributor to the catalog. Exhibition announcement; letters to TYF from Dominique G. Mazeaud, Project Manager, Ceremony of Memory, 1/19/89; 2/24/89; 5/5/89; letter [unaddressed - to TYF, or to the participating artists of Ceremony of Memory] from Dominique G. Mazeaud [unsigned but on his stationery], 5/1/89, re. exhibition he was curating in Poland; clippings; catalog, Ceremony of Memory: New Expressions in Spirituality Among Contemporary Hispanic Artists, Center for Contemporary Arts of Santa Fe, Santa Fe, NM, 1988)
  - Ceremony of the Spirit (see also: Mesa-Bains, Amalia), 1988 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    (TYF's notes on/from Ceremony of the Spirit, ethnic studies; catalog, Kingdoms of the Sun: Masterworks of Ancient Andean and Spanish Colonial Art, Mint Museum of Art, Charlotte, NC, 1996; letter to TYF from Juan [?], 4/30/88, re. bookstores in San Antonio and in Mexico City; clippings; invitation to dance gala performance)
  - Cervántez, Yreina D., 1988; (clipping) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - César Chávez Center (see also: Baca, Judith; SPARC), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    (organization, University of California at Los Angeles; Witness to the History of Los Angeles project; booklet, final product, of student-produced public art project by the UCLA / César Chávez Center Mural Digital Lab at the Social and Public Art Resource Center and co-sponsored by Cornerstone Theater Company)
  - Chacón, George, circa 2003 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    (exhibition announcement; blank note cards with artist's work; mini-CD business cards)
  - Chagoya, Enrique (see also: Artists' Books; Gómez-Peña, Guillermo), 1989-2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    (catalogs, When Paradise Arrived, Alternative Museum, New York, 1989; and Utopian Cannibal: Adventures in Reverse Anthropology, Forum for Contemporary Art, St. Louis, Missouri, 2001; exhibition announcements; clippings; artist book, Codex Espangliensis from Columbus to the Border Patrol, Moving Parts Press, Santa Cruz, 1998; announcement and publicity booklet)
  - Chaves, Estelle, 1965; (photocopies from an exhibition catalog) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Chávez, César, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    (clippings including NY Times obituary; dance performance announcement, tribute to Chavez; memorial services announcement)
  - Chávez, Eduardo (see also: Covarrubias, Miguel), 1987-1988, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    (note and letter to TYF re. information TYF requested about Miguel Covarrubias, 12/87 and 12/29/87; exhibition announcement)
  - Chávez, Roberto Esteban (see also: Carrillo, Eduardo), 1978-1981, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    (resume; part of a report [on public art and legalities involved] including a section concerning Roberto Chavez and the destruction of his mural at East Los Angeles College, and part of a section concerning Eduardo Carrillo; clippings; letter to TYF from Philip Brookman re. a grant proposal, 07/21/91)
  - Chavoya, C. Ondine, 1995-1996, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    (dissertation abstract; resume; manuscript draft, "Undocumented Histories From the West"; photocopy of "Collaborative Public Art and Multimedia Installation: David Avalos, Louis Hock, and Elizabeth Sisco's Welcome to America's Finest Tourist Plantation, 1988")
  - Chicana Artists (see also: Lopéz, Yolanda; Mesa-Bains, Amalia), 1998; (catalog) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Chicana/o Art of San Diego, Exhibition, University of San Diego, San Diego, California, 2004; (catalog) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Chicana/o Arts and Social Action, Organization, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    (conference announcements; Spring 2003 Speaker Series "Chicanas/os in Higher Education" announcements (lecture given by TYF); conference report for "Revolution & Resistance: A Conference on the State of Chicana/o Art & Activism.")
  - Chicanacán: Semana de Arte y Cultura Chicana en México, Exhibition, Mexico City, Mexico, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    (two letters to Gustavo Sainz - responsible for promotion, housing, transportation and financing of the project in Mexico City - from the Comoté Chicanacán, 02/15/1980 and 09/04/1980; letter to TYF from Comité Chicanacán, 04/18/80, re. the cancellation of the project)
  - Chicanarte, Los Angeles Municipal Art Gallery, 1975; (see also: Box 30; OV 32) (Box 6, Folder 16)
    (exhibition announcement/performance schedule; article published by the Comité Chicanarte, not included in catalog; oversize exhibition poster; oversize catalog order form/poster; clippings)
  - Chicana Artistas (see also: Baca, Judith; Barrazza, Santa; Carrasco, Barbara; Esperanza Peace and Justice Center; Galeria de la Raza/Studio 24; Gamboa, Diane; Goldman, Shifra; Hernandez, Ester; Lopez, Yolanda; Lucero, Linda; Mesa-Bains, Amalia; Rayas; SPARC), 1970-1975, 1982-1998; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
    (clippings; exhibition announcement; photocopies of art; exhibition announcements; La Voz de Esperanza magazine, Esperanza Peace and Justice Center, Dec 97/Jan 98; letter to TYF from Mary Lou Nevarez Haugh, 9/12/89, re. book she wanted to write on Latina artists in California; exhibition list; catalog, signed by Shifra Goldman, guest curator; clippings; photocopy of the Bibliography from Third Woman, vol. 4, 1989, Third Woman Press, Berkeley)
  - Chicanismo (see: Lecture Notes) (Box 6)
  - Chicanismo en el Arte, Exhibition, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1975; (exhibition announcement; catalog) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Chicano and Latino Artists in the Pacific Northwest, Exhibition, Evergreen State College, Olympia, Washington (see also: Alvarez, Cecilia; Arreguín, Alfredo; Rodriguez, José Luis; Trejo, Ruben; White, Sid and Pat; Ybarra-Frausto, Tomas), 1980, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    (catalog; Letter to TYF from Sid and Pat White, 09/09/2004; "Chicano and Latino Artist in the PNW" - project history, circa 2004)
  - Chicano Architectural Students Association, Organization, University of California at Berkeley, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    (monograph, Our Barrios: Past, Present, and Future: A Look at Raza/Latinos and the Built Environment, Chicano Architectural Students Association, University of California at Berkeley, Berkeley, 1983)
  - Chicano Art for Our Millennium, Exhibition, Mesa Southwest Museum Hispanic Research Center of Arizona State University, 2004; (invitation to exhibition opening reception) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Chicano Art (Box 6)
    - Arte Chicano Como Cultura de Protesto, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      (monograph - Sylvia Gorodezky, Arte Chicano Como Cultura de Protesta, Mexico City, Mexico: Universidad Nacionla Autónoma de México, 1993)
    - Chicano Art History (see also: Quirarte, Jacinto), 1984 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      (monograph - Jacinto Quirarte, ed. Chicano Art History: A Book of Selected Readings, San Antonio, TX: Research Center for the Arts and Humanities, The University of Texas at San Antonio)
    - General, 1975-1977, circa 1984, circa 1985 (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
      (typescript of curatorial note or introduction for an exhibition catalog; typed drafts and notes, "Introdución a la Historia del Arte México-Americano"; TYF's notes - "Chicano Art: A Precis"; clippings; TYF's notes and handwritten drafts; clippings; clipping of article by TYF - "A History of Chicano Art" from Revista Literaria de el Tecolote, circa 1980; draft with edits and photocopy of the typescript of an essay by and unknown author)
  - Chicano Art and Culture, Exhibition, United States and Europe (see also: Aztlán), 1980 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    (documents related to the planning of the exhibition: list of committees, meeting minutes and agendas, budgets, etc.)
  - Chicano Art: Resistance and Affirmation (CARA), University of California at Los Angeles (Box 6)
    - Albuquerque, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      (invitation; note to TYF from Chon [Noriega], 07/27/91; film series announcement; calendar of events; clipping)
    - Arizona, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      (symposium brochure; calendar of events; letters to TYF from University of Arizona, Tuscon, 10/09/91, and from Robert A. Yassin, Tuscon Museum of Art, both re. request that TYF be the keynote speaker at a symposium being held in conjunction with CARA; exhibition announcement for Counter Colón-ialismo; TYF's travel itinerary; photograph [of TYF and ?])
    - Artists Directory, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      (letter to TYF from Ava Avalos, CARA Archivist, 08/30/1991, with enclosure of CARA Artist Directory)
    - Bronx Museum of Art, 1993; (exhibition announcement; invitation) (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Clippings, General, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Denver, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      (letter to TYF from Farida Baldnado, Curatorial Assistant, CARA, 07/10/91, re. Denver's education report for the CARA exhibition; comments from the exhibition guestbook)
    - Education Packets, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      (K-6 and 7-12 education packets: slides, information for teachers, glossary, pre- and post-visit activities)
    - General, 1986-1993 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      ( New Art Examiner Dec. 1990 issue, cover article on CARA; dissertation proposal, "'Mi Casa [No] Es Su Casa': The Cultural Politics of the Chicano Art: Resistance and Affirmation, 1965-1985 Exhibit", Alicia Gaspar de Alba, University of New Mexico, 1992; "The Power of Place" (UCLA Graduate School of Architecture & Urban Planning Embassy Auditorium public art project) proposal for Rockefeller Foundation funding: cover letter, 08/16/1990, narrative proposal, budget, supporting materials; "Artes de México" Festival: memo to committee, 08/27/1990, list of committee members, fax, 09/20/1990; press release; invitation to lecture focusing on "The Contadora Process and the Beyond War Award"; Texas Small Press Book Fair announcement; calendar from Sacramento City Councilman Joe Serna; Mississippi American Festival Project calendaer of events; CARA exhibition calendar of events, Fresno Art Museum; clippings; May/June 1993 issue of La Peña: Latino Arts News)
    - Los Angeles, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      (press releases; fact sheet; clippings; calendars of events; exhibition announcements; letter to TYF from Elizabeth Shepard, 08/27/1990, inviting him to opening of the exhibition; invitations)
    - Lynne Cheney/NEH, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      (letter to Steven Ross, NEH, from Brigette D. Scott, Community Development Assistant, Wight Art Gallery, 08/31/1989, re. application for the NEH Summer Seminars for College Teachers program and Ross' response, 10/20/1989, with the comments from the evaluators; letter to Edith Tonelli from Marsha Semmel, NEH, re. application for NEH funding for CARA, 12/20/1989 with review comments; letter to Edith Tonelli from Thomas Wilson, NEH, 05/18/1989, re. application for funding from NEH, with review comments; photocopy of letter to Lynne Cheney, Chairman National Endowment for the Humanities, from the CARA Exhibition Executive Board, 12/16/1989 and Cheney's response, 12/21/1989)
    - Mexican Fine Arts Center Museum, Chicago, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      (correspondence: 2 copies, one labeled Tomás, of letter to Edith Tonelli from Carlos Tortolero, Executive Director, 01/15/987; memo to co-chairs of the CARA steering committee from Edith Tonelli, 01/28/1988; letter to Carlos Tortolero from Edith Tonelli, 01/28/1988)
    - NEH Implementation Grant, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      (draft, "Compañeros and Partners - CARA: the Process"; NEH Implementation Grant material)
    - Photographs, 1971, 1979; (photographs of works of art) (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Planning, 1986-1987; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 41-43)
      (NEH Interim Report, 1987; NEH planning conference agenda & accompanying handouts; TYF's notes from conference; list of exhibition panel members; list of participants; general letters to TYF from Edith Tonelli, et al. re. plans for the conference; clippings; press release; "Guidelines for Regional Presentations"; meeting agendas and minutes; letter to TYF from Marcos [Sanchez], re. second planning July 1987 conference and "pre-meeting packet;" notes and letters to TYF from CARA organizers re. his participation; correspondence between CARA organizers and institutions re. the exhibit; memos to CARA steering committee; press release; letter to TYF from Holly Barnet- Sanchez and Marcos Sanchez re. "document which represents the formative stages of the conceptual framework for the exhibition" and said document, 08/05/1988; TYF's notes; catalog planning; meeting agendas, minutes, and summary report; budget documents; exhibition tour planning; exhibition checklist (fax); clippings; CARA Curriculum Seminars course description; CARA education summary; essay, " Murales de Movimiento: Chicano Murals and the Discourses of Art and Americanization", by Marcos Sanchez-Tranquilino (cc: TYF); correspondence between CARA and the National Museum of American Art, re. the exhibition; "Compañros and Partners - CARA: The Process")
  - Chicano Art: Resistance and Affirmation continued (Box 7)
    - Planning, circa 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      (slides; checklist of exhibition; CARA evaluation)
    - Planning, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      (letter to Constance Wolf, Rockefeller Foundation, from Cindi Dale, Director Education and Community Development, Wight Art Gallery, 04/16/1990, re. CARA education program; general correspondence between CARA organizers and institutions re. the exhibition; letter to TYF from Elizabeth Shepard inviting him to loan two pieces of art, 02/12/1990; invitation to private tour of CARA at UCLA; letter to TYF from Chon [Noriega], 08/08, re. CARA Film & Video Series; program copy of CARA Film & Video Series; letter to John Lane, Director San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, from Marcos Sanchez-Tranquilino, 06/17/1991, and response, 07/09/1991; essay, "The Political and Social Contexts of Chicano Art" by Shifra M. Goldman and TYF; CARA travel schedule)
    - Planning - Catalog Drafts, circa 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      (draft of components of the catalog; letter to TYF from Teresa McKenna, Editorial Board, CARA, 03/30/1989, re. TYF's essay for catalog; correspondence between Ray Rocco, Director National Association of Chicano Studies Conference, and CARA organizers, 03/1989, re. Silkscreen Print Taller Exhibition)
    - Planning - NEH Proposal, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)